

SENIOR ROBOTICS RESEARCH ENGINEER

New York City, NY, USA

□ (+1) 347-294-8197 | wivekrk44@gmail.com | wivekrk44

Summary.

Proactive Robotics researcher and engineer specialized in autonomous unmanned aerial vehicles with 10+ years of experience delivering multiple industrial solutions, including long-range GPS denied navigation for unmanned aerial systems as well as heterogeneous swarms of aerial robots for maximum area coverage. Driven by an ongoing quest for knowledge and a dedication to solving complex challenges with exceptional proficiency across both hardware and software domains.

Education

Masters (New York University, Tandon School of Engineering)

New York, USA

M.S. IN MECHATRONICS AND ROBOTICS ENGINEERING

2021 - 2023

• 2 years research experience at Agile Robotics and Perception Lab under Prof. Giuseppe Loianno

Bachelors with Honors (Birla Institute of Technology and Science)

Dubai, UAE

B.S. IN ELECTRICAL AND ELECTRONICS ENGINEERING

2010 - 2014

Skills_

Programming C++, C, Embedded C, Python, Bash, C#, .NET, VHDL, Verilog

Softwares ROS, Unity3D, Arduino, STM32Cube, Vim, Keil, Matlab, OpenSCAD, KiCAD, Git, Jenkins, Docker, Xilinx ISE

Hardware PCB Design, Embedded system circuit design, SMD/Through hole soldering **Embedded Systems** PX4, Crazyflie, STM32, VOXL, NVIDIA Jetson, Raspberry Pi, Xilinx Spartan

Work Experiences _____

ZEROFLAi New York, USA

CO-FOUNDER & CEO Jul. 2023 - Present

Bridging drone innovation from research to industry

• Autonomous charging system for UAVs for perpetual autonomous missions without a human in the loop

Technology Innovation Institute

Abu Dhabi, UAE

SENIOR RESEARCHER HARDWARE DESIGN

Jul. 2020 - Aug. 2023

Worked as a research engineer building state of the art autonomous UAVs (fixed wings, multirotors and VTOLS)

- Fully automated system design for test platforms Quadcopter and FixedWing VTOL
- Unified control architecture for quadcopters and fixed wings
- Implemented non linear controller and planner for high speed aggressive quadcopter flights greater than 100 miles per hour
- Multi sensor fusion using an **Unscented Kalman Filter**
- Designed a cascaded multi filter approach (EKF & PDAF) to track incoming objects while removing false positives
- ${\bf Mission\ commander}$ with tight integration with ${\bf QGroundControl}$
- Custom **UI** for **commander** and **control** modules
- · Full hardware system design

Algorythma Autonomous Aerial Labs

Abu Dhabi, UAE

Systems Integration Engineer

Oct. 2018 - June. 2020

Worked as the system integration engineer in the Autonomous Aerial Lab of Algorythma. Designed and implemented cutting edge control, state estimation, perception and other critical subsystems which were implemented on the aerial platform.

- Developed a **unified swarming subsystem** to command or control the UAVs
- Designed and implemented a **geometric controller** for **trajectory tracking**
- Designed a minimum snap trajectory generator and sampler
- Built a custom sensor fusion system using EKF
- Designed and implemented a **globally consistent state estimation** for swarming application
- Implemented an online 3D mapping using RGBD camera
- Custom designed a GUI for feedback and control
- Developed scripts for easy system setup
- Implemented CI for important subsystems using Jenkins and Docker
- PCB design and development for different subsystems

BUT nv. Dubai, UAE

HARDWARE DEVELOPER / LEAD HARDWARE ENGINEER

May. 2015 - Sept. 2018

BUT nv is an interactive media company. Promoted to the role of lead hardware engineer on December of 2017. The projects I was involved in are as follows.

- Built RC car with FPV and lap timer which was controlled with steering wheel and used for racing
- Backend implementation for an in house Robotic Al assistant
- Implemented control of ABB Yumi robotic hand using Playstation controller at MWC 2018
- Created an interface that connected Unity 3D with ABB Yumi using RAPID
- Built a touchscreen using a Hokuyo Lidar and integrated with in house content
- Designed and built 4D Virtual Reality systems which would trigger additional experience like water mist, scent, rumble etc
- Reverse engineering of black box systems
- Developed custom software for holographic fans, which allow multiple fans to sync content and display a large format video
- Designed the **networking protocols** and seamless **player tracking** for a **multiplayer virtual reality** experience
- Implemented user tracking in a large scale interactive Augmented Reality project
- Used Crazyflie 2.0 as an autopilot for a swarm of 6 mini quadcopters in a dance
- Integrated **custom sensors** in the **smart mirror** platform to detect parameters like height, weight, temperature, breathing rate etc
- Created **6dof trackable paper** to be used as control for a projection mapping table
- Implemented and merged face analytics API into in house solutions
- Built a prototype concept for the smart living room, with features that include key finder, knock controller, smart wallpaper etc
- Full 6DOF tracking of an object using PNP algorithm and a single camera
- Designed and implemented a software to analyze and add motion to 360 video
- Server maintenance and optimization for the Guzzle app
- Built and delivered workshop for university students that include OpenCv, Arduino and using microcontrollers with computers
- Built an object detection/recognition api using machine learning for Unity 3D

The Assembly Dubai, UAE

In House Engineer Oct. 2014 - May. 2015

As the in house engineer of the Assembly my job was to build amazing projects and deliver workshops on different topics like Robotics, IOT etc. The workshops presented are as follows

- Basics of IOT The scope of this workshop was to give an introduction on IOT, IOE and introduce the AllJoyn library from Qualcomm
- Advanced IOT This workshop was to continue where we left off on the previous workshop and introduce and teach the library
- Learning Computer Vision In this session the goal was to introduce OpenCV and teach the basic Image Processing functions and implement simple algorithms
- Learning Gesture Control This program introduces people to the Leap Sensor and shows them how to leverage the hand tracking library to control robots
- Basics of UAVs This workshop introduces the participants to UAV's and tells them about the basic concepts of flight, control etc. They are also given DIY kits and told how to assemble and quadcopters.
- Smart Home Automation It introduced the Arduino Platform and how to leverage it to detect environmental changes using sensors and react accordingly
- DIY Security Camera This workshop uses OpenCV optical flow algorithm to detect movement and take a video and upload it on the cloud.
- How do Robots See Implementing an obstacle avoidance algorithm and improving it was the main objective of this workshop

Etisalat. Dubai, UAE

 UAV Engineer
 Dec. 2014 - Feb. 2015

After the success of the UAV project in GITEX 2014, Etisalat entered the Drones for Good Award, where we won the 1st place. There were 2 projects submitted. One was a portable RF station/monitor. The second one was using drones to transport polio vaccines to remote locations.

- Developed a path planning and obstacle avoidance algorithm
- Implemented **non linear control system** for low power consumption flights
- Designed an **autonomous charging** scheme and **route optimizations** for long endurance flight
- Interfacing the sensor stack and Etisalat modem with the controller
- Full software stack development

Etisalat. Dubai, UAE

UAV ENGINEERAug. 2014 - Oct. 2014

Worked as a consultant and developer for the Drone aspect of the Smart City Project. My responsibilities were

- Develop a multi-rotor platform for carrying heavy payloads
- Programming the customized controller
- Implemented 3D terrain mapping
- Designed and implemented control system
- Integration of ${\bf sensor}\,{\bf stack}$ with ${\bf controller}$

Samsung and Acer Dubai, UAE

DMOTER Feb 2013 and Oct 2012

Worked as a Promoter for Samsung in Gitex Shopper 2013 and Acer in Gitex Shoppers 2012

Peer-Reviewed Publications

Unifying Foundation Models with Quadrotor Control for Visual Tracking Beyond Object Categories

0 ,

Yokohama, Japan

May 2024

S

Directed Graph Topology Preservation in Multi-Robot Systems with Limited Field of View Using Control Barrier Functions

New York, USA

IEEE Access

Dec 2023

AutoCharge: Autonomous Charging for Perpetual Quadrotor Missions

London, UK

IEEE INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON ROBOTICS AND AUTOMATION (ICRA) 2023

IEEE INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON ROBOTICS AND AUTOMATION (ICRA) 2024

May 2023

Vision-based Relative Detection and Tracking for Teams of Micro Aerial Vehicles

Kyoto, Japan

IEEE/RSJ INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON INTELLIGENT ROBOTS AND SYSTEMS (IROS) 2022

Oct. 2022

Challenges in Vision-based Drones Navigation at IROS 2019

Macao, China

IEEE/RSJ INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON INTELLIGENT ROBOTS AND SYSTEMS (IROS) 2019

Nov. 2019

Patents

A system for charging a battery in an aircraft

U.S. Provisional Patent

PROVISIONAL - GRANTED (No. 63/375,638)

Sept, 2022

A system for charging a battery in an aircraft

U.S. Utility Patent

UTILITY - PENDING (No. 18/467,202)

Sept, 2023

Extracurricular Activities

Team IFOR Dubai, UAE

ENGINEER, TECH LEAD IN 2012

2011 - 2014

- Implementing Path Planning and Obstacle Avoidance on ROS
- Integrating other key software components with ROS
- Integration of all software with ROS
- Porting ROS to ARM
- Implemented Kalman Filter for sensor fusion
- Implemented 2D Exploration algorithm on ROS
- Implemented Non-Linear Control system

College Projects Dubai UAE

Self project 2010 - 2014

- Design and implement a miniature fingerprint based attendance monitoring system
- Implementation of SLAM algorithm on a microcontroller with integrated DSP
- · Design and implement an obstacle avoidance algorithm using Reinforcement learning on a UGV platform
- Harvesting usable energy from Piezo-Electric Crystals
- Implemented a multi sensor platform for automobile safety
- · Design a simple math co-processor on a FPGA